So in closing, the office of a director
is one of the high health office, is
not to be taken lightly.
So before you accept your next board seat,
or if you're already sitting on the board,
you want to ask yourself, have I done
my due diligence?
Do I understand the extent of my responsibilities
as a director?
Is this worth taking my reputation for?
And if I'm going to accept the office
of a director, I want to continue in
that office, am I ready to do the
work?
I'm not supposed to take, or I'm not
expected to take all that management sells me
as gospel.
I need to do my research and understand
the business of the company.
The second thing I want to say, if
you're sitting on multiple boards right now, you
have to ask yourself, do you have the
capacity to give your best to all of
the boards on which you're sitting?
So maybe it's time to do an audit
of all the boards you're sitting on.
Which one do you consider to be a
nuisance?
And doesn't give you the fulfilment that you
deserve?
Because you really can't over-stretch yourself and
like I said, there's a term now known
as being over-bordered.
If you're more than, I don't want to
give you a number, but if you know
that you have reached your capacity to accept
or to do well on the boards you're
sitting on, do an audit and please drop
one or two.
You can recommend somebody else in your place.
If you've been sitting on the board for
a while and the board hasn't done an
assessment of its performance or your performance, feedback
is critical to your continued effectiveness.
So it's important to call the board's attention
to the need to undertake the board evaluation
of the entire board and the peer review
of individual's performance.
This enables you to get feedback, real-time
feedback from your colleagues and from the consultants
on how well you as a director have
done and how well the board has done.
And more importantly, identify areas of gap that
can then be drilled into an action plan
for yourself as a director and for the
board as a whole.
And that brings us to the end of
the session.
For more information and additional resources, please click
on the link attached to this presentation.
Thank you very much.